Nikolaev Dmitry Ivanovich

I focus on applied mathematics and telecommunications, particularly in the areas of queueing theory, stochastic modeling, and teletraffic systems. My work includes developing mathematical models for analyzing network performance, optimizing system processes, and solving real-world telecommunication challenges. I actively collaborate with other researchers and participate in international conferences to present findings and share insights.

nikola.dmitryy@icloud.com
https://mrshogun.github.io/ru/

+7(919)-964-08-44

7 Sevanskaya St., Moscow

EXPERIENCE

RUDN University, Department of Probability Theory and Cyber Security

Research assistant October 2024 – Present

 Work as an executor under the grant of the Russian Science Foundation № 24-19-00804, , on the theme: "Study of Age of Information in the problems of quality assurance of URLLC and mMTC services in 5G wireless networks" at the Department of Probability Theory and Cyber Security of the Institute of Computer Science and Telecommunications, Faculty of Science.

Research assistant October 2023 – October 2024

 Worked as an executor under the grant of the Russian Science Foundation № 23-79-10084, , on the theme: "Mathematical models and practical algorithms for improving energy efficiency in heterogeneous millimetre and terahertz networks of the fifth and sixth generation (5G/6G)" at the Department of Probability Theory and Cyber Security of the Institute of Computer Science and Telecommunications, Faculty of Science.

EDUCATION

RUDN University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science - 4.96 GPA

September 2020 - June 2024

Graduated with honours with a Bachelor's degree in Mathematics and Computer Science. Thesis
on analysis of boundary Integrated Access and Backhaul network node using polling service
models.

Professional retraining "Teacher of Mathematics"

March 2024 - June 2024

 Studied under the programme of additional professional education "Teacher of Mathematics" at Interfaculty Centre for Further Professional Education (ICFPE) "Perspektiva" of the Faculty of Science.

Professional retraining "Translator"

September 2020 - June 2024

 Studied under the programme of additional professional education "Translator" in the areas and specialities of the Faculty of Science (English-Russian) at Department of Foreign Languages of the Faculty of Science.

SKILLS

Data analysis •••••
LaTeX ••••

English • • • • • Julia • • • • •

Data visualisation ••••

Python •••

- Mathematical modelling: Creation and research of network models. Development of mathematical models of teletraffic and queueing systems
- Probability theory: Queueing theory, Stochastic processes, Markov processes
- Academic writing: Writing articles and reports for international conferences and publications
- Writing and communication: Clearly and effectively express ideas in written and verbal form to audiences with varying levels of expertise
- Analytical and critical thinking: Analyzing complex data, identify patterns, critically evaluating information and methodologies, and draw well-founded conclusions.